Guide to the Jack Miles papers MS.F.045
Special Collections and Archives, University of California, Irvine Libraries
Jack Miles papers
1950-2022
1904-2022
Special Collections and Archives, University of California, Irvine Libraries
MS.F.045
18.15 Linear Feet (14 records cartons, 4 document box, 1 flat box, 1 trophy box, 1 small artifact box, 1 audiovisual box, 1 digital media box, and 1 oversize folder)
0.00705 Gigabytes (15 digital files)
This collection comprises the papers of Jack Miles, Pulitzer Prize winning author, MacArthur Fellow, and Distinguished Professor Emeritus of English and Religious Studies at the University of California, Irvine. The papers consist of professional, scholarly, and personal materials documenting his life and career, including publications, books, correspondence, teaching materials, speaking engagements, fellowships and memberships, and biographical material.
Access
The collection is open for research. Access to original audiovisual material and digital media is restricted; researchers may request viewing or listening copies.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Jack Miles, 2017-2022.
Biography
John R. "Jack" Miles is a Pulitzer Prize winning author, MacArthur Fellow, and Distinguished Professor Emeritus of English & Religious Studies at the University of California, Irvine.
Miles was born in Chicago, Illinois, on July 30, 1942. He attended high school at St. Ignatius College Preparatory School. Between 1960-1970, he was a Jesuit seminarian studying at the Pontifical Gregorian University in Rome and the Hebrew University in Jerusalem. He completed a Ph.D. in Near Eastern languages at Harvard University in 1971.
Miles is a writer whose work has appeared in The Atlantic, The New York Times, The Washington Post, The Los Angeles Times, The Boston Globe, Commonweal, among others. His book God: A Biography won a Pulitzer Prize in 1996 and has been translated into sixteen languages. A sequel to the book entitled, Christ: A Crisis in the Life of God, was published in 2001 and led to Miles being named a MacArthur Fellow in 2002. The third book in the God in Three Classic Scriptures series, God in the Qur'an, was published in 2018. In 2022 Miles published another books titled,'A Friendship in Twilight: Lockdown Conversations on Death and Life' with Mark C. Taylor, composed of letters written by the pair between March 15 to May 14, 2020 detailing their thoughts on the Covid-19 Pandemic, racial inequality in US, higher education, the 2020 election, religion, philosophy,family, history, and a host of other topics.
Between 1975 and 1995, Miles was an editor at Doubleday; executive editor at the University of California Press; literary editor at the Los Angeles Times; and a member of the Times Editorial Board, writing on politics and culture. For ten years, he served on the Committee of Selection of the John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation. He was also the general editor of The Norton Anthology of World Religions, which was published in 2014.
Miles is a Distinguished Professor Emeritus of English and Religious Studies at the University of California, Irvine, and Senior Fellow for Religion and International Affairs with the Pacific Council on International Policy. He has been a Mellon Visiting Professor of Humanities at Caltech, Director of the Humanities Center at the Claremont Graduate University, Scholar in Residence and Senior Advisor at the J. Paul Getty Trust, and a Visiting Fellow with the Committee on the Conceptual Foundations of Science, University of Chicago.
Miles is married to Catherine "Kitty" Miles and is the father of Kathleen Miles.
Collection Scope and Content Summary
This collection comprises the professional and personal papers of Jack Miles, which document his career as a writer, editor, and professor of English and Religious Studies. Materials in the collection include drafts and copies of his books and articles, unpublished works, edited anthologies and articles, correspondence, teaching materials, speaking engagements, fellowships and memberships, and biographical material which includes documentation of his early life, high school memorabilia, and awards.
Collection Arrangement
The collection is organized in the following six series:
Writings and editing, 1969-2021. 9.75 linear feet and 0.00102 GB
Correspondence, 1960-2021. 2.2 linear feet
Teaching materials, 1966-2017. 0.75 linear feet
Speaking engagements, 1975-2021. 1 linear foot
Fellowships and memberships, 1997-2008. 0.5 linear feet
Biographical, 1904-2021. 2.75 linear feet and 0.00602 GB
Writing and correspondence, 2019-2022
Appraisal Note
During processing the collection was reduced from 23.75 linear feet to 16.95 linear feet by discarding duplicate materials, material under the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA), and materials outside of the scope of the collection.
Additional Collection Guides
A file list inventory of the digital files is available via this link: Jack Miles papers born digital directory.
- Writings and editing, 1969-2021; Series 1.
  Series Scope and Content Summary
  This series consists of material related to books written by Miles; an extensive collection of articles, essays, reviews, and op-eds written by Miles; his doctoral thesis, written in November 1970; material related to his time as general editor of the Norton Anthology of World Religions; and works he contributed to publications or collaborated on with other authors and artists. The series also contains correspondence, photographs and negatives, digital media, research files, and notes in relation to the writings and editings.
  Series Arrangement
  The series is arranged in its original order.
  - Books, circa 1983-2021; Subseries 1.1
    Scope and Content Note
    This subseries consists of material related to the three books written by Jack Miles in the God in Three Classic Scriptures series: God: A Biography, Christ: A Crisis in the Life of God, and God in the Qur'an. It includes early versions, drafts, first-pass proofs and uncorrected proofs of the works; notes about the design of the books and revisions; publicity and articles about the books and winning the Pulitzer Prize in 1996 for God: A Biography; interviews; reviews; and correspondence. It also contains some digital files (see Additional Collection Guides for access), floppy disks, and audio cassettes related to the books. The subseries also contains drafts of and materials relating to the books Religion As We Know It: An Origin Story (2019) and A Friendship in Twilight: Lockdown Letters on Death and Life with Mark C. Taylor. Some folders contain notes from Jack Miles in 2017 to provide more context about the materials.
    - God/The Lord God, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - God/The Suicide of God the Son, undated (Box 3, Folder 1-2)
    - God: A Biography draft, 1995 (Box 3, Folder 3-6)
    - Christ: A Crisis in the Life of God jacket notes and correspondence on design and last revisions, 2000-2002 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - "God", 2001-2003 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - God: A Biography and Pulitzer Prize publicity, 1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 6-7)
    - Christ: A Crisis in the Life of God reviews and related, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Christ: A Crisis in the Life of God publicity, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - God: A Biography reviews (Engl.), 1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Knopf, 1994-1995 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Jesus German publicity, 2001-2002 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Reviews and correspondence pertaining to 'Christ', circa 2001-2002 (Box 9, Folder 24-25)
    - Two God: A Biography letters, 1995-1999 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Interview relating to God: A Biography, 1997 May 20 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Notes on the chapter of God: A Biography devoted to the Book of Job, circa 1983-1994 (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Christ: A Crisis in the Life of God book review in the New York Times, 2001 December 23 (Box 12, Folder 23)
    - Christ: A Crisis in the Life of God copy-edited typescript, 2001 (Box 12, Folder 24-25)
    - Christ: A Crisis in the Life of God first-pass proofs, with hand-corrections by Miles, 2001 June 1 (Box 12, Folder 26-27)
    - Two letters from Germany and France related to God: A Biography in translation, circa 2002 (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - God in the Qur'an, copyedited version, 2018 February 10 (Box 13, Folder 7-8)
    - God in the Qur'an typescript, 2017-2018 (Box 13, Folder 18-21)
    - God in the Qur'an first pass, 2018 (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - God in the Qur'an drafts, 2018 (Box 13, Folder 31, Box 14, Folder 1-2)
    - God: A Biography uncorrected proof with annotations, 1995 April (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - God in the Qur'an uncorrected proof, 2018 November 14 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Qur'an supplements, 2007, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Qur'an materials, 2006-2015, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - God in the Qur'an, 2002-2017 (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - God in the Qur'an reviews, 2018-2019 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - God in the Qur'an promotional materials, 2016-2018 (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - God in the Qur'an quote sources, 2006-2018 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Religion As We Know It: An Origin Story, 2019-2020 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - A Friendship in Twilight: Lockdown Letters on Death and Life draft, 2020-2021 (Box 15, Folder 10-12)
      Scope and Contents Note
      Written with Mark C. Taylor during the COVID-19 pandemic.
    - Unprocessed audiovisual material and digital media, circa 1990s (Box 19, Box 20)
      Includes floppy disks, CDs, flash drives, and audiocassettes.
  - Articles, essays, thesis, and reviews, 1969-2021; Subseries 1.2
    This subseries consists of articles, essays, op-eds, reviews of other people's work, his doctoral thesis, and unpublished writings by Jack Miles. It includes writings featured in the Los Angeles Times, The Atlantic, Commonweal, The New York Times, The Washington Post, The Boston Globe, as well as various journals, anthologies, and websites. The topics of the articles range from the Iraq War to climate change, from the Los Angeles riots in the 1990s to same-sex marriage. The subseries also contains clippings from when Miles served as Los Angeles Times editor. Some folders include correspondence, drafts, notes, research, photographs, and other material related to each piece of writing. Some folders contain notes from Jack Miles in 2017 to provide more context about the materials.
    - Los Angeles Times, The Pulitzer Prizes in Journalism: Category 11, Distinguished Editorial Writing, Jack Miles on the Ward Valley Nuclear Dump, 1993 (Box FB-020, Folder 10)
    - "God", 1997-1998 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Book reviews, 2003 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - "Religion and American Foreign Policy", Survival (IISS), Spring, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 12-14)
    - Opinion (1 of 4): "Our King George Faces a Reckoning", Los Angeles Times commentary, 2004 May 16 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Opinion (2 of 4): Jesus/gay marriage, Los Angeles Times, 2004 February 29 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Opinion (3 of 4): "Court's No Place for Pettiness", Los Angeles Times, 2004 December 5 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Opinion (4 of 4): "Bad News for Jews", Los Angeles Times, 2004 November 7 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Mel Gibson's "Passion of the Christ" review, Evening Standard, 2004 February 24 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - 2004 book reviews (1 of 2): "Coming of Age in Chicago" (Ward Just) book review, New York Times, 2004 July 25 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - 2004 book reviews (2 of 2): "Was Jesus American?" book review, Jerusalem Post, 2004 April 9 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - "Deep in the Heart of Florida", Commonweal, 2004 December 3 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Why Iraq Resists, undated (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - "Portrait of the Pope as a Dying Man", Los Angeles Times, 2005 April 1 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - New York Times op-ed, circa 1990-1996 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - Los Angeles Times editorial clippings, 1978-1995 (Box 5, Folder 13-18)
    - Column - Belief.com, 1999-2001 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - "Is Lebanon Israel's Iraq?", The Jewish Journal of Greater Los Angeles, 2006 August (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Article index, 2004 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Jesus Before He Could Talk, 1995 December 24 (Box FB-020, Folder 10)
    - You Won't Believe Who I Just Saw!, 2003 May 11 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - "The Jungle of Desire", Commonweal, 2003 April 11 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - "Our Lady of the Freeways", Commonweal, 2003 February 28 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - "Countdown to War: Iraq and the next 9/11", Los Angeles Times, 2003 February 2 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - Comments on Walter Wink, 2002 November 24 (Box 5, Folder 29)
    - "Theology and the Clash of Civilizations", CrossCurrents, Winter, 2002 (Box 5, Folder 32)
    - "The Loyal Opposition", New York Times book review, 2002 July 14 (Box 5, Folder 35)
    - "Flagging Attention to Etiquette", Los Angeles Times, 2002 June 30 (Box 5, Folder 36)
    - Retelling a Struggle for Christianity, 1999 September 5 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - "A Leap of Faith", Los Angeles Times, 2002 April 28 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - "Getting Away with Murder: How We Let Genocide Happen", The New York Observer, 2002 April 6 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - "The Nazis, the Pope, the Shoah- Weighing their Sins and Ours", The New York Observer, 2002 March 11 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - "On the Uses of a Metaphor", Authors Guild Bulletin, Fall, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Faires des musulmans occidentaux des alliés de l'intérieur, Los Angeles Times, 2001 October 31 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - "The Muslim Ally Within", Los Angeles Times, 2001 September 23 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - "Three Differences Between an Academic and an Intellectual...", CrossCurrents, Fall, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Unsere Auβenminister müssen Theologie lernen, 2001 September (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - "Happily Ever After", Commonweal, 2001 August 17 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - "Global Requiem: The Apocalyptic Movement in Religion, Science, and Art", CrossCurrents, Fall, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - "Casting Genesis: George Segal's Biblical Sculptures", Bible Review, 2000 April (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - "Millennial Dilemmas", Tikkun, 2000 January (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - "What Does the Bible Say About Bosnia?", Religion and Values in Public Life, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 15)
    - "Jacob's Wrestling Match: Was it an Angel or Esau?", Abraham and Family, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 16)
    - "A Complicated God", The Changing Face of God, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 17)
    - "The Good Booklets", National Review, 1999 December 31 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - "There's a Time When Only Poetry Will Do", Los Angeles Times, 1999 September 5 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - "The Different Definitions of Terrorism", Washington Post, 1999 July 17 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - "Over the Body of a Dead Actress", Los Angeles Times, 1999 July 4 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - "The Senate's Makeup Distorts the National Agenda", The Boston Globe, 1998 November 12 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Corporate Leadership and the Media, 1998 October 1 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - "Poetry and the Sacred", Partisan Review, Winter, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - "Death in Venice", New York Times book review, 1998 September 20 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - "Forgiveness for Our Prodigal President", The Boston Globe, 1998 September 17 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - A Crime of Passion, 1998 February (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - A Response from Jack Miles (to Mary Douglas), 1998 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - "The Nihilist and the Inventor", The Republic of Letters, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - "Apologia pro biblioteca sua", Harvard Divinity Bulletin, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - "Religion Makes a Comeback (Belief to Follow)", New York Times Magazine, 1997 December 7 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - "Velcro Man Meets Teflon Story", Commonweal, 1997 July 18 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - "The Workforce, the Web, and the Freelance Writer", Center, Spring, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - "On the Road to Damascus", Washington Post, 1997 March 30 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - "On a Mission from God", New York Times book review, 1997 January 5 (Box 6, Folder 37)
    - "What Belgrade's Protestors are Telling the West", The Christian Science Monitor, 1996 December 17 (Box 6, Folder 38)
    - "God's Next Life", New Perspectives Quarterly, Spring, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 39)
    - Review of The Life of God (As Told By Himself), undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
    - "The Ghost of a Christmas Past", New York Times book review, 1995 December 10 (Box 6, Folder 41)
    - Review of Dictionary of Biblical Tradition, 1995 November 1 (Box 6, Folder 42)
    - "As We See It", Company: A magazine of the American Jesuits, Fall, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 43)
    - "Educational Malpractice", National Review, 1995 July 18 (Box 6, Folder 44)
    - L.A.gie, 1995 July 12 (Box 6, Folder 45)
    - "Looking at the Lord as a Literary Character", The Boston Sunday Globe, 1995 April 16 (Box 6, Folder 46)
    - "A Literary Reading of the Book of Proverbs", Commonweal, 1995 March 10 (Box 6, Folder 47)
    - "Acclaimed Poet James Merrill dies", Los Angeles Times, 1995 February 18 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    - "Political Correctness and the American Newspaper", English Today, 1995 January (Box 6, Folder 49)
    - "Confessions of a Recidivist Bible Scholar", Harvard Divinity Bulletin, 1995 June 17 (Box 6, Folder 50)
    - Asking the Bible for More, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 51)
    - "The Epiphanies of Love and Loss", Los Angeles Times, 1994 November 13 (Box 6, Folder 52)
    - A Modest Proposal, 1994 November (Box 6, Folder 53)
    - "A Death in the L.A. Family", Los Angeles Times, 1994 June 17 (Box 6, Folder 54)
    - "A Bold Proposal on Immigration", The Atlantic Monthly, 1994 June (Box 6, Folder 55)
    - "What Does the Bible Say About Bosnia?", Religion and Values in Public Life, Fall, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 56)
    - "Erwin Glikes; Publisher of Social Criticism", Los Angeles Times, 1994 May 17 (Box 6, Folder 57)
    - Sticks and Stones, 1994 April 3 (Box 6, Folder 58)
    - "The Alternative to Anarchy", Contention: Debates in Society, Culture, and Science, Spring, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 59)
    - "Auschwitz and Sarajevo", Tikkun, 1994 March (Box 6, Folder 60)
    - "What Would Moses Say?", Los Angeles Times, 1994 January 3 (Box 6, Folder 61)
    - "An Artist of American Violence", The Atlantic, 1993 June (Box 6, Folder 62)
    - "What Has Happened to the New Yorker?", Los Angeles Times, 1993 April 25 (Box 6, Folder 63)
    - "Bad Times: Unemployment is Death...", The Boston Sunday Globe, 1993 March 14 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - "Blacks vs. Browns", Race and Ethnic Relations, 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - "Blacks vs. Browns", Sociocultural Issues in Education, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Letter to Buzz, 1992 December 28 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Review of The First Dissident, 1992 December 20 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - The Myopia of the Los Angeles Elite, 1992 December (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - "Blacks vs. Browns", The Atlantic, 1992 October (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - "Riot Poetry: A Sampler", Los Angeles Times, 1992 May 24 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Alone with God, 1992 May 12 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - "In Impious America", A Journal of Archetype and Culture, Spring, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - "A Life With Latin", St. Ignatius Magazine, Spring, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - "Imagining Mayhem", The North American Review, 1991 December (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - "The 'Dictatorship of Mediocrity'", Los Angeles Times, 1991 July 7 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - Reviews of Book of J, undated (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - "The Free Speech Struggle", Los Angeles Times, 1991 January 6 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - "The Book of B", Commonweal, 1990 November 9 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - Of Book Reviewing and Brotherly Love, undated (Box 7, Folder 18)
    - "'Book of J' Lacks Nerve to Name 'J'", Los Angeles Times, 1990 October 13 (Box 7, Folder 19)
    - How Mesopotamia Became Iraq, circa 1990 (Box 7, Folder 20)
    - The Sacrament of Hospitality, circa 1990 (Box 7, Folder 21)
    - "On Reviewing Popular Books", Publishers Weekly, 1990 July 27 (Box 7, Folder 22)
    - Tom Wolfe's Literary Manifesto: A Response, undated (Box 7, Folder 23)
    - "A Survivor's Story", Los Angeles Times, 1990 May 16 (Box 7, Folder 24)
    - Mr. Hanabusa Has a Point, 1990 March (Box 7, Folder 25)
    - Walkyries (unpublished), undated (Box 7, Folder 26)
    - "Review of Thomas More: A Biography", Los Angeles Times, 1984 October 28 (Box 7, Folder 27)
    - The Perils of Pluralism, 1990 (Box 7, Folder 28)
    - "UC Tenure: a Forest of Deadwood", Los Angeles Times, 1989 August 13 (Box 7, Folder 29)
    - "The Economics and Politics of Book Reviewing", Chronicles, 1989 September (Box 7, Folder 30)
    - Plotting the O.C. Novel, 1987 October 4 (Box 7, Folder 31)
    - "Walk Along the Coast in Donegal", Commonweal, circa 1987 (Box 7, Folder 32)
    - Sins, circa 1985 (Box 7, Folder 34)
    - "How to Lose Money Electronically", Library Journal, 1984 November 15 (Box 7, Folder 35)
    - Christopher Isherwood's Promise, 1984 November 4 (Box 7, Folder 36)
    - Review of The Turning Point, 1984 June (Box 7, Folder 37)
    - Of a Complementary Dilemma in Organized Science and Organized Religion, 1983 December (Box 7, Folder 38)
    - The Decision to Publish, 1983 September (Box 7, Folder 39)
    - "Searching for God - and Adulthood", Commonweal, 1983 May 20 (Box 7, Folder 40)
    - Radical Editing, circa 1980-1981 (Box 7, Folder 41)
    - Letter to Alan? on John Lynch, 1980 October 30 (Box 7, Folder 42)
    - The University Press and the American Mind, 1979 May 25 (Box 7, Folder 43)
    - "Primitive Ritual and Christian Totemism", Commonweal, 1979 April 13 (Box 7, Folder 44)
    - "Religion Behind the Curtain", National Review, 1979 March 16 (Box 7, Folder 45)
    - Review of Review of Man of Nazareth and a Life of Jesus, 1979 (Box 7, Folder 46)
    - "From Unspeakable to Ineffable", The Nation, 1978 July 1 (Box 7, Folder 47)
    - "Cruel Sport, and Little More", The Nation, 1977 December 24 (Box 7, Folder 48)
    - Review of Raid on the Articulate, 1977 April (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - Burhoe, Barbour, Mythology, and Sociobiology, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - "Is You or is You Ain't My Baby?", National Review, 1977 January 7 (Box 7, Folder 51)
    - A Theological Book of Lists, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 52)
    - "Gagging on Job", Semeia 7, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 53)
    - "What Committee Hath Wrought...", Commonweal, 1976 December 3 (Box 7, Folder 54)
    - The Teaching of Social Science, 1976 November (Box 7, Folder 55)
    - "The Debut of the Bible as a Pagan Classic", The Council on the Study of Religion Bulletin, 1976 June (Box 7, Folder 56)
    - From Barth to Barthes, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 57)
    - "Knowing the Score at Scholars Press", Scholarly Publishing, 1976 April (Box 7, Folder 58)
    - The Ontological Status of Our Inquiry Denied, 1976 March (Box 7, Folder 59)
    - Review of Catholicism Confronts Modernity, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 60)
    - "Catholicism as a Protestantism", Theology Today, 1976 January (Box 7, Folder 61)
    - Equus and the Death of Psychiatry, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 62)
    - "Understanding Albricht: A Revolutionary Etude", Harvard Theological Review, Volume 69:1-2, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 63)
    - Jain and Judaeo-Christian Respect for Life, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 64)
    - Hyde Park - Today I Started Loving You Again, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 65)
    - Reviews of Essays in Biblical Culture, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 66)
    - A Child's Garden of Publishing Wisdom, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 68)
    - Review of Myths, Models, and Paradigms, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 69)
    - Apostle of Marcuse?, 1975 May (Box 7, Folder 70)
    - Ancestor Identity Brings Rebirth, 1975 January 22 (Box 7, Folder 71)
    - Review of Works of Albright, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 72)
    - "Laughing at the Bible: Jonah as Parody", The Jewish Quarterly Review, Volume LXV, Fall, 1974 (Box 7, Folder 73)
    - "Religious Claims to Palestine", Worldview, 1974 August (Box 7, Folder 74)